<resourceInfos>
  <resourceInfo category="Genome"
                contact="Wes Warren"
                displayName="T. cruzi cruzi JR cl. 4 genome sequence."
                email="wwarren@genome.wustl.edu"
                institution="wustl"
                organisms="@@TcruziJRcl4OrganismFullName@@"
                project="TriTrypDB"
                publicUrl=""
                resource="TcruziJRcl4_contigs_RSRC">
    <description>
<![CDATA[
        
<b>Background</b>
<br />
<p>The Trypanosome cruzi JR strain cl4 was obtained from Dr. Gregory Buck, Center for the Study of Biological Complexity, Microbiology and Immunology, Virginia Commonwealth University.  This strain, a representative of the TcI lineage of T. cruzi (Hamilton et al., 2011), was isolated from a male patient, age 55, in chronic symptomatic stage of disease in Anzoategui, Venezuela . A clonal derivative was prepared from epimastigote culture by plating on blood agar plates (M. Lewis) and used for sequencing.  </p>
<br />
<p>Genomic DNA was depleted for kinetoplast (mitochondrial) DNA (kDNA), which represents up to 30-50% of the total DNA in the cell, by Andrey Matveyev. In brief, total DNA was extracted from cultured late log phase T. cruzi JR epimastigote forms and submitted to low voltage electrophoresis in 0.8% low melting agarose. The gDNA-containing agarose blocks were excised from the gel, leaving the kDNA networks intact in the gel. Purified gDNA was recovered from the agarose blocks after digestion using Beta-agarase I.</p>
<br />
<p>The gDNA was fragmented and sequenced using the Roche 454 FLX Titanium technology and a draft assembly was produced. Total sequence coverage from the Roche 454 technology was ~50X (fragments =~ 22X, 3 Kb paired end (PE) =~ 20X, 8 Kb PE =~ 6.5X) using a genome size estimate of 40 Mbp. The combined sequence reads were assembled using the Newbler software (Roche 454). This first draft assembly was referred to as T._cruzi_JR cl4-1.1. The assembly is made up of a total of 20,846 scaffolds with an N50 scaffold length of over 67kb (N50 contig length for the 25,491 contigs was 3.9kb). The assembly spans 41Mb. This assembly is subject to change due to ongoing assembly improvement efforts.</p>
<br />
<p>This work was supported by NSF DEB-0830056 grant to Gregory Buck and by NIH-NHGRI grant 5U54HG00307907 to RKW, Director of The Genome Center at Washington University.</p>
<br />
<p>For questions regarding this T_cruzi_JR cl4-1.1_assembly please contact Dr. Wes Warren, Washington University School of Medicine (wwarren@genome.wustl.edu). Downloads of the sequence data are available via the TriTrypDB genome browser server. Funding for the sequence characterization of the Trypanosoma cruzi JR cl4 strain genome was provided by the National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI), National Institutes of Health (NIH).</p>
<br />
<b>Credits</b>
<br />
<p>DNA source  Myrna G. Serrano, Andrey Matveyev, Ana Lara and Gregory Buck Center for the Study of Biological Complexity & the Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Virginia Commonwealth University., Richmond, VA</p>
<br />
<p>Parasite source  Michael Miles and Michael D. Lewis, Medical Protozoology, London School of Hygiene & Tropical Medicine, London, England.</p>
<br />
<p>Sequencing - The Genome Center, Washington University School of Medicine, St Louis, MO. </p>
<br />
<p>Sequence assembly  The Genome Center, Washington University School of Medicine, St Louis, MO.</p>
<br />
<b>Citation upon use of this assembly in a manuscript</b>
<br />
<p>It is requested that users of this Trypanosoma cruzi JR cl4 strain sequence assembly acknowledge Gregory A. Buck, Virginia Commonwealth University, and The Genome Center, Washington University School of Medicine in any publications that result from use of this sequence assembly.  Any publications that propose to use whole genome or chromosome data should contact The Genome Center at Washington University (gweinsto@wustl.edu or wwarren@wustl.edu) for the use of pre-publication data.  Please refer to the Genome Center Data Use Policy (http://genome.wustl.edu/data/data_use_policy) for further information regarding proper use of data and proper citation. </p>
<br />
<p>Miles MA, Toye PJ, Oswald SC, Godfrey DG. The identification by isoenzyme patterns of two distinct strain-groups of Trypanosoma cruzi, circulating independently in a rural area of Brazil. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 1977; 71: 217-25.</p>
<br />
<p>Brisse S, Barnabé C, Tibayrenc M. Identification of six Trypanosoma cruzi phylogenetic lineages by random amplified polymorphic DNA and multilocus enzyme electrophoresis. Int J Parasitol. 2000; 30: 35-44.</p>
<br />
<p>Zingales B, Andrade SG, Briones MR, Campbell DA, Chiari E, Fernandes O, Guhl F, Lages-Silva E, Macedo AM, Machado CR, Miles MA, Romanha AJ, Sturm NR, Tibayrenc M, Schijman AG; Second Satellite Meeting. A new consensus for Trypanosoma cruzi intraspecific nomenclature: second revision meeting recommends TcI to TcVI. Mem Inst Oswaldo Cruz. 2009; 104: 1051-4.</p>
        
       ]]>
</description>

    <wdkReference recordClass="SequenceRecordClasses.SequenceRecordClass" type="attribute" name="overview"/>
    <wdkReference recordClass="SequenceRecordClasses.SequenceRecordClass" type="question" name="GenomicSequenceQuestions.SequenceBySourceId"/>
    <wdkReference recordClass="SequenceRecordClasses.SequenceRecordClass" type="question" name="GenomicSequenceQuestions.SequencesByTaxon"/>
    <wdkReference recordClass="SequenceRecordClasses.SequenceRecordClass" type="question" name="GenomicSequenceQuestions.SequencesBySimilarity"/>


  </resourceInfo>
</resourceInfos>
